Featherweight Heroes.
Valiant is a family, animation, adventure film directed by Gary Chapman.
Set in 1944, Valiant is a woodland pigeon who
wants to become a great hero someday.
When he hears they are hiring recruits for the Royal Homing
Pigeon Service, he immediately sets out for London.
On the way, he meets a smelly but friendly pigeon named Bugsy, who joins him, mainly to get away from
clients he cheated in a game of find-the pebble, and helps him sign up for the war.
Valiant (voice), played by Ewan McGregor.
Bugsy (voice), played by Ricky Gervais.
Von Talon (voice), played by Tim Curry.
Sergeant (voice), played by Jim Broadbent.
Gutsy (voice), played by Hugh Laurie.
Mercury (voice), played by John Cleese.
Valiant is a 2005 animated comedy film produced by John H.
Williams and directed by Gary Chapman.
It is the first feature film by American animation studio Vanguard Animation.
The ensemble voice cast includes Ewan McGregor, Ricky Gervais, Tim Curry, Jim Broadbent, Hugh
Laurie, John Cleese, John Hurt, Pip Torrens, Rik Mayall, and Olivia Williams.
Set in May 1944, the film follows of a group of war pigeons during World War II.
It was inspired by true stories of hundreds of pigeons
that helped the soldiers in the war.
Valiant was released in the United Kingdom on 25 March
2005, and in the United States on 19 August.
It received mixed reviews from critics, and grossed $62
million against a $35 million budget.
The film explores themes of villain, animals, pigeon.
The tone is lighthearted.